Records of the Education Sector
World Bank Group Archives
- Partnerships and program collaboration, 1978 - 2003, 2007; WB IBRD/IDA WB_IBRD/IDA_88-02; 17.37 linear feet of textual records
  - World Conference on Education for All Subject Files - Basic Education for All Conference [BEAC] Washington - Working Group Meeting - Paris - November 16 - 18, 1988 - Volume 2, 1988-03-12; 30327791
  - World Conference on Education for All Subject Files - Executive Committee Minutes - WCEFA Executive Committee Meeting - New York - May 21, 1990 - Volume 2, 1990-04-11 - 1990-06-12; 30327780
  - World Conference on Education for All Subject Files - Executive Committee Minutes - WCEFA Executive Committee Meeting - New York - May 21, 1990 - Volume 1, 1990-04-11 - 1990-06-12; 30327779
  - World Conference on Education for All Subject Files - Executive Committee Minutes - WCEFA Executive Committee Meeting - New York - January 12, 1990 - Volume 2, 1990-01-12 - 1990-01-19; 30327778
  - World Conference on Education for All Subject Files - Executive Committee Minutes - WCEFA Executive Committee Meeting - New York - January 12, 1990 - Volume 1, 1990-01-12 - 1990-01-19; 30327777
  - World Conference on Education for All Subject Files - Executive Committee Minutes - WCEFA Executive Committee Meeting - Nice - December 13 and 16, 1989 - Volume 3, 1989-12-13 - 1989-12-16; 30327776
  - World Conference on Education for All Subject Files - Executive Committee Minutes - WCEFA Executive Committee Meeting - Nice - December 13 and 16, 1989 - Volume 2, 1989-12-13 - 1989-12-16; 30327775
  - World Conference on Education for All Subject Files - Executive Committee Minutes - WCEFA Executive Committee Meeting - Nice - December 13 and 16, 1989 - Volume 1, 1989-12-13 - 1989-12-16; 30327774
  - World Conference on Education for All Subject Files - Executive Committee Minutes - WCEFA Executive Committee Meeting - New York - August 7 - 8, 1989 - Volume 2, 1989-07-25 - 1989-08-08; 30327773
  - World Conference on Education for All Subject Files - Executive Committee Minutes - WCEFA Executive Committee Meeting - New York - August 7 - 8, 1989 - Volume 1, 1989-07-17 - 1989-08-09; 30327772
  - World Conference on Education for All Subject Files - Executive Committee Minutes - WCEFA Executive Committee Meeting - Paris - March 13 - 14, 1989 - Volume 2, 1989-02-02 - 1989-03-14; 30327769
  - World Conference on Education for All Subject Files - Heads of Agencies Meeting - Executive Secretary Progress Reports - Volume 2, 1989-03-31 - 1989-08-30; 30327752
  - World Conference on Education for All Subject Files - Heads of Agencies Meeting - Executive Secretary Progress Reports - Volume 1, 1989-03-31 - 1989-08-30; 30327751
  - World Conference on Education for All Subject Files - Heads of Agencies Meeting - Washington - 6 February 1989 - Volume 1, 1988-10-22 - 1989-03-01; 30327747
  - World Conference on Education for All Subject Files - Executive Committee Minutes - WCEFA Executive Committee Meeting - Washington - May 12 - 13, 1989 - Volume 2, 1989-05-08 - 1989-05-13; 30327771
  - World Conference on Education for All Subject Files - Executive Committee Minutes - WCEFA Executive Committee Meeting - Washington - May 12 - 13, 1989 - Volume 1, 1989-04-26 - 1989-05-13; 30327770
  - World Conference on Education for All Subject Files - Heads of Agencies Meeting - 31 January 1990 - Volume 2, 1990-01-31; 30327750
  - World Conference on Education for All Subject Files - Heads of Agencies Meeting - New York - 31 January 1990 - Volume 1, 1990-01-29 - 1990-01-31; 30327749
  - World Conference on Education for All Subject Files - Heads of Agencies Meeting - Washington - 6 February 1989 - Volume 2, 1988-10-13 - 1989-03-28; 30327748
  - World Conference on Education for All Subject Files - Heads of Agencies Meeting - New York - 22 October 1988 - Volume 2, 1988-10-22; 30327746
  - World Conference on Education for All subject files: discussion paper No 95 - education and development, evidence for new priorities - set, 1990-08-27; 01134455
  - World Conference on Education for All subject files: World Bank financing of education, lending, learning and development (Ph.W. Jones) - set, 1991-01-19; 01134454
  - World Conference on Education for All subject files: ilustrativa general - 25v, 1990-01-01 - 1990-03-09; 01134453
  - World Conference on Education for All subject files: rivodtablen documents, thematic - 24v, 1984-09-01 - 1990-03-09; 01134452
  - World Conference on Education for All subject files: NF/MRP telefaxes - set, 1989-10-06 - 1990-06-29; 01134451
  - World Conference on Education for All Subject Files - Press Coverage, 1989-12-11 - 1990-04-11; 01134450
  - World Conference on Education for All subject files: declaration general - 2v, 1990-02-27 - 1990-03-06; 01134449
  - World Conference on Education for All subject files: regional consultations minutes, reports - set, 1989-06-16 - 1990-01-23; 01134448
  - World Conference on Education for All Subject Files - Regional Consultations - List of Participants, 1989-11-06 - 1990-01-23; 01134447
  - World Conference on Education for All Subject Files - Steering Group A to B - Volume 1, 1989-08-31 - 1990-07-16; 01134446
  - World Conference on Education for All Subject Files - Steering Group - Chronological Records - Volume 1 - 1987 - 1990, 1987-11-04 - 1990-02-13; 01134442
  - World Conference on Education for All subject files: Steering Group proposala for membership - set, 1988-11-16 - 1989-06-18; 01134441
  - World Conference on Education for All subject files: legal agreements - 2v, 1989-03-03 - 1989-10-06; 01134440
  - World Conference on Education for All Subject Files - Heads of Agencies Meeting - New York - 22 October 1988 - Volume 1, 1988-10-22; 01134439
  - World Conference on Education for All subject files: World Bank general - set, 1989-01-01 - 1989-08-31; 01134431
  - World Conference on Education for All Subject Files - WCEFA All Sponsors Initial Meeting - New York - August 9, 1989 - Volume 1, 1989-08-09; 01134438
  - World Conference on Education for All Subject Files - WFCEFA Steering Group Meeting - Paris - October 12 - 14, 1989 - Volume 1, 1989-09-28 - 1989-10-14; 01134437
  - World Conference on Education for All Subject Files - Basic Education for All Conference [BEAC] Washington - Working Group Meeting - Paris - September 8 - 9, 1988 - Volume 1, 1988-09-08 - 1988-09-09; 01134436
  - World Conference on Education for All Subject Files - Executive Committee Minutes - WCEFA Executive Committee Meeting - Paris - March 13 - 14, 1989 - Volume 1, 1989-03-03 - 1989-03-14; 01134435
  - World Conference on Education for All subject files: NGOs general - set, 1989-06-22 - 1989-10-25; 01134434
  - World Conference on Education for All subject files: World Health Organization (WHO) - set, 1989-04-17 - 1990-07-16; 01134433
  - World Conference on Education for All subject files: World Food Program - set, 1989-04-03 - 1989-11-10; 01134432
  - World Conference on Education for All subject files: Van Leer Foundation - set, 1989-04-03 - 1990-02-06; 01134430
  - World Conference on Education for All subject files: UNDP general - set, 1989-01-01 - 1989-12-31; 01134429
  - World Conference on Education for All subject files: UNDP (Bangkok) general - set, 1989-04-28 - 1989-05-13; 01134428
  - World Conference on Education for All subject files: UNFPA general - set, 1989-03-29 - 1990-07-16; 01134427
  - World Conference on Education for All subject files: UNICEF (Bangkok) general - set, 1989-01-01 - 1990-08-31; 01134424
  - World Conference on Education for All subject files: United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees (UNHCR) - set, 1989-12-14; 01134423
  - World Conference on Education for All subject files: Research Review and Advisory Group (NORRAG) - set, 1989-01-01 - ?; 01134388
  - World Conference on Education for All subject files: UNESCO (Bangkok) general - set, 1989-01-01 - 1990-08-31; 01134425
  - World Conference on Education for All subject files: USSR general - set, 1989-04-10 - 1990-07-16; 01134422
  - World Conference on Education for All subject files: Switzerland general - set, 1989-04-25 - 1990-07-16; 01134421
  - World Conference on Education for All subject files: Swedish International Development Authority (SIDA) - set, 1989-04-03 - 1990-07-16; 01134420
  - World Conference on Education for All subject files: Southeast Asian Ministers of Education Secretariat (SEAMED) - set, 1989-06-02 - 1989-06-21; 01134419
  - World Conference on Education for All subject files: Rockefeller Foundation - set, 1989-06-14 - 1989-10-04; 01134418
  - World Conference on Education for All subject files: Portugal general - set, 1989-06-14 - 1989-09-15; 01134417
  - World Conference on Education for All subject files: Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development (OECD) - set, 1989-04-22 - 1989-12-20; 01134416
  - World Conference on Education for All subject files: Organization of African Unity (OAU) - set, 1989-04-13 - 1989-06-01; 01134415
  - World Conference on Education for All subject files: Overseas Development Administrator (ODA) - set, 1989-06-14 - 1989-11-14; 01134390
  - World Conference on Education for All subject files: Norway general - set, 1989-04-03 - 1990-07-16; 01134389
  - World Conference on Education for All subject files: New Zealand general - set, 1989-01-01 - ?; 01134387
  - World Conference on Education for All subject files: Netherlands general - set, 1990-01-01 - ?; 01134386
  - World Conference on Education for All subject files: International Organization of Consumers Unions (IOCU) - set, 1989-01-01 - ?; 01134377
  - World Conference on Education for All subject files: Japan Ministry of Foreign Affairs - set, 1989-03-28 - 1990-07-16; 01134384
  - World Conference on Education for All subject files: IWGE general - set, 1989-08-09 - 1989-09-06; 01134383
  - World Conference on Education for All subject files: Italy general - set, 1990-01-01 - ?; 01134382
  - World Conference on Education for All subject files: Ireland general - set, 1989-01-01 - ?; 01134381
  - World Conference on Education for All subject files: International Telecommunication Union (ITC) - set, 1989-01-01 - ?; 01134380
  - World Conference on Education for All subject files: International Task Force on Literacy (ITFL) - set, 1989-01-01 - ?; 01134379
  - World Conference on Education for All subject files: International Reading Association - set, 1989-01-01 - ?; 01134378
  - World Conference on Education for All subject files: International Labour Organization (ILO) - set, 1989-01-01 - ?; 01134376
  - World Conference on Education for All subject files: International Fund for Agricultural Development (IFAD) - set, 1990-01-01 - ?; 01134375
  - World Conference on Education for All subject files: International Development Research Center (IDRC) - set, 1989-01-01 - ?; 01134374
  - World Conference on Education for All subject files: Internal Council of Adult Education (ICAE) - set, 1990-01-01 - ?; 01134373
  - World Conference on Education for All subject files: Islamic Educational Scientific and Cultural Organization - set, 1989-01-04 - 1990-07-16; 01134369
  - World Conference on Education for All subject files: Internal Bureau of Education (IBE) - set, 1989-01-01 - ?; 01134372
  - World Conference on Education for All subject files: Inter-American Development Bank (IDB) - set, 1989-01-01 - ?; 01134371
  - World Conference on Education for All subject files: Inter Action - set, 1989-01-01 - ?; 01134370
  - World Conference on Education for All subject files: Economic and Social Commission for Asia and the Pacific (ESCAP) - set, 1990-01-01 - ?; 01134350
  - World Conference on Education for All subject files: Economic Commission for Latin America (ECLAC) - set, 1989-01-01 - ?; 01134349
  - World Conference on Education for All Subject Files - Consultation of Major Funding Agencies - 1989, 1989-04-03 - 1989-09-15; 01134313
  - World Conference on Education for All subject files: France general - set, 1989-01-01 - ?; 01134368
  - World Conference on Education for All subject files: Food Foundation - set, 1989-01-01 - ?; 01134365
  - World Conference on Education for All subject files: Food and Agriculture Organization (FAO) - set, 1989-01-01 - ?; 01134363
  - World Conference on Education for All subject files: FINNIDA general - set, 1989-01-01 - ?; 01134360
  - World Conference on Education for All subject files: Economic and Social Commission for Western Asia (ESCWA) - set, 1989-01-01 - ?; 01134351
  - World Conference on Education for All subject files: Economic Commission for Africa (ECA) - set, 1989-01-01 - ?; 01134348
  - World Conference on Education for All subject files: Deutsche Stiftung fur Internationale Entwicklung (DSE) - set, 1989-01-01 - ?; 01134347
  - World Conference on Education for All subject files: DANIDA general - set, 1990-01-01 - ?; 01134346
  - World Conference on Education for All subject files: Council of Europe - set, 1989-01-01 - ?; 01134344
  - World Conference on Education for All subject files: Commonwealth Secretariat - set, 1989-01-01 - ?; 01134310
  - World Conference on Education for All subject files: Canada International Development Agency (CIDA) - set, 1990-01-01 - ?; 01134305
  - World Conference on Education for All subject files: African Development Bank (ADB) - set, 1989-01-01 - ?; 01134297
  - World Conference on Education for All subject files: agency file - set, 1989-01-01 - ?; 01134298
  - World Conference on Education for All subject files: Commission of the European Communities - set, 1989-01-01 - ?; 01134309
  - World Conference on Education for All subject files: Centro de Investigacion y Desarollo de la Educacion - set, 1989-01-01 - ?; 01134308
  - World Conference on Education for All subject files: Carnegie Corporation of New York - set, 1989-01-01 - ?; 01134306
  - World Conference on Education for All subject files: British Council - set, 1989-01-01 - ?; 01134304
  - World Conference on Education for All subject files: Belgium general - set, 1989-01-01 - ?; 01134303
  - World Conference on Education for All subject files: Australia general - set, 1989-01-01 - 1990-12-31; 01134301
  - World Conference on Education for All subject files: Asian Development Bank (ADB) - set, 1989-01-01 - ?; 01134300
  - World Conference on Education for All subject files: Arab Literacy and Education Organization - set, 1989-01-01 - ?; 01134299
- Knowledge and learning events, 1985, 1997 - 2005; WB IBRD/IDA WB_IBRD/IDA_88-03; 3.11 linear feet of textual records
  Series consists of records related to a variety of conferences, seminars, and other knowledge and learning events organized or attended by senior management and staff across the sector's units. Records include internal memoranda, incoming and outgoing letters, agendas, presentation slides, course or training materials, and copies of journal articles and papers.
  Many records document HDNED Director Ruth Kagia's participation and presentations in various conferences and other external and internal events. There are files containing mostly presentation slide transparencies outlining Poverty Reduction and Strategy Paper (PSRP) training, as well as Kagia's presentation to the Non-Governmental Organization (NGO) Conference on User Fees in Education held 23 April 2001 discussing the World Bank's position on user fees. Also includes Kagia's paper presentation at the 2002 International Conference of the Centre of African Studies under the topic of new approaches to African development that are filed with letters from conference donors, a list of participants, invitations, and copies of papers presented by other speakers.
  Records related to Human Development Week 2000 contain talking points and data under the heading of poverty and human development, including an overview of Human Development Network (HDN) goals, immediate indicators, and future indicators. There are also hard copy emails to and from Kagia and other Bank staff including Human Development Poverty Reduction Economist Michael Walton regarding planning and content, course materials, and communications and evaluations for Humane Development Learning Week (2003).
  The series also contains records of Bank-hosted and organized learning events. These include the global Early Childhood Development (ECD) Conference hosted by the Bank in April 2000 to address the benefits and challenges of investing in early child development. The records include some administrative correspondence on preparation and planning of the conference. There is also a file related to the Bank seminar on the international development goals for multilateral development partners and member country development institutions, hosted in March 2001 and organized outside of HDNED, but which Kagia attended. Included are the list of participants, agenda, data slides, background papers, and reports.
  A variety of other files relate to: briefing materials and key education documents for various conferences and seminars attended by sector staff as well as Bank President James D. Wolfensohn (1997 - 2003); minutes, report of the Knowledge Board and staff learning progress report (2004 - 2005); year-end reports, evaluations, activity initiation report status and course descriptions (1999 - 2000).
  There is also a small volume of records pertaining to the Seminar on Public Expenditures that was developed by the Education Policy Division (EDTEP) and held in 1985.
  Records were transferred to the Archives by the Education Team, Human Development Network (HDNED) and predecessor units in multiple transfers between 1992 and 2011 in accordance with approved records schedules.
  * See Records of the Education Sector - Director and Front Office records ([WB IBRD/IDA WB_IBRD/IDA_88-01](https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/director-and-front-office-records-1)) for other records related to the management and oversight of the sector staff training program, and other training activities.
  * See Records of the Education Sector - Operations research ([WB IBRD/IDA WB_IBRD/IDA_88-10](https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/operations-research)) for records regarding conferences, workshops, or other events attended by sector research staff, including the Research Priorities in Education in Sub-Saharan Africa Conference.
  * See Records of the Education Sector - Partnerships and program collaboration ([WB IBRD/IDA WB_IBRD/IDA_88-02](https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/partnerships-and-program-collaboration)) for records regarding the World Conference on Education for All (WCEFA) and Bank partnerships with multilateral development partners, NGOs, and other external organizations in the education sector.
  * See Records of the World Bank Institute ([WB IBRD/IDA WBI](https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/records-of-world-bank-institute)) for records related to education sector training program and courses.
  - Seminar on Public Sector Expenditures, 1985 - set, 1985-01-01 - ?; 01103620
  - Poverty Reduction Strategy Paper [PRSP] - Training Slides Human Development Week - 2000, 2000-05-31; 30037779
  - From Consensus to Action - A Seminar on the International Development Goals - 2001, 2000-11-16 - 2001-03-20; 30037778
  - Kagia, Ruth - User Fees in Education Non - Governmental Organization [NGO] Conference - 23 April 2001, 2001-04-23; 30037777
  - A New Approach to African Development - Annual International Conference, 2002-05-11 - 2002-06-30; 30037776
  - International Consultative Forum on Education for All - Steering Committee - 12th Meeting - October, 1999 - Correspondence, 1997-10-01 - 2000-03-02; 01677088
  - ECD Conference 2000 - Speakers Bio-Sketches - Correspondence, 2000-03-01 - 2000-03-31; 01677080
  - ECD Conference 2000 - Reimbursement - Correspondence, 2000-04-01 - 2000-07-31; 01677077
  - ECD Conference 2000 - Payments and Registrations - Correspondence, 1999-09-01 - 2000-05-01; 01677075
  - ECD Conference 2000 - Payments to Speakers - Correspondence, 2000-04-01 - 2000-08-31; 01677074
  - ECD Conference 2000 - Logistics and Conference Organizers - correspondence, 1999-07-01 - 2000-05-31; 01677071
  - ECD Conference 2000 - Invitees and Participants - Correspondence, 1999-10-01 - 2000-03-31; 01676941
  - Briefing Materials - Education - Lifelong Learning and The Knowledge Economy Conference - Stuttgart, Germany - October 9 - 10, 2002, 2002-10-09 - 2002-10-10; 30123627
  - Key Education Documents - Given To Jim Socknat and Shobhana Sosale May 2002 For Preparation of Education Sector Board [ESB] Not For Quality Assurance Group [QAG] Sector Board, 2000-10-11 - 2003-05-12; 30123626
  - Education Group of the Human Development Network [HDNED] - Key Education Documents, 2000-10-11 - 2002-08-23; 30123625
  - 2003 Human Development Learning Week - Course Materials and Communications, Evaluations, Registrations - November 2003, 2003-10-16 - 2003-11-14; 30060571
  - Education Training - Learning Minutes and Report of Knowledge Board - Staff Learning Progress Report - Fiscal Year [FY] 2006, 2004-07-01 - 2005-09-16; 30060570
  - Education Training - Year End Reports, Evaluations, Activity Initiation Report Status, Course Descriptions - Fiscal Year [FY] 2000, 1999-11-23 - 2000-08-13; 30060569